《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
恭喜你  博士
Congratulations, Doctor.
你刚发现了第一个赛昂人
You've just uncovered your very first Cylon.
我不是赛昂人
I'm not a Cylon.
这不是真的
BOOMER: This isn't happening.
我都在这呆了几个月了  独自逃亡
I've been here for months, by myself, on the run,
赛昂人在后面紧追不舍
one step ahead of the Cylons.
快去  不然我让你脑袋开花
CRASHDOWN: You're going out there or I'm gonna blow your brains out
就在此时此地
right here, right now.
克莱斯当怎么死的
APOLLO: How did Crashdown die?
他以最光荣的形式献出了自己的生命
He gave his life in the finest tradition of the service.
我向你发誓  在我当值的时候
You have my parole. When I'm on duty
我不会试图释放她
I'll make no attempt to free her
或是在船员之间煽动叛乱
or sow insurrection among the crew.
下班以后  我直接到牢房里报道
And when I'm not on duty, I'll report directly back to this cell.
我还能活几个月
I have a few months to live.
在这段时间里  我将带领人民脱离苦难
And in that time, I will lead the people to salvation.
这是我个人意愿
It is my sole purpose.
显然
As it appears obvious that
政府无法在当前形势下继续运作
the Government cannot function under the current circumstances,
我已决定解散12法人团体
I have decided to dissolve the Quorum of 12.
此时此刻
And as of this moment
我宣布实施戒严令
I have declared martial law.
你流汗了
TIGH: You're sweating.
这里热
It's hot in here.
沃莱瑞中尉计划刺杀阿达玛指挥官
How long have you known
这事你知道多久了?
Lt. Valerii was planning to assassinate Commander Adama?
我并不知道她在计划什么事
I had no idea she was planning anything of the kind.
你和她上床了
You were frakking her.
我按你的命令  在几周前就和她分手了
I ended that weeks ago on your orders.
你包庇她  替她说谎
You covered for her, you lied for her.
我承认我一时糊涂
I admit I used bad judgment.
你时刻都在保护她
You protected her at every turn.
上校  我不知道她是赛昂人
Colonel, I had no idea she was a Cylon.
这次我要行使第21号条款中的权利
I would like to exercise my Article 21 rights at this time.
早料到了
I'm sure you would.
我看你还没听说吧  赛昂人可没有权利
I guess you haven't heard, Cylons don't have rights.
赛昂人?等等
Cylon? Wait a minute...
你知道我们是怎么处置赛昂人的吗  上士?
You know what we do with Cylons, Chief?
我不是赛昂人
I am not a Cylon.
罗丝琳提出的行刑方法
Roslin came up with the execution method.
我是加伦·蒂罗尔!
I'm Galen Tyrol.
她把一个赛昂人放到了过渡舱外
She put a Cylon out of the airlock.
我父亲曾是一名牧师  母亲曾是一名神使
My father was a priest. My mother was an oracle.
我从18岁就开始在太空堡垒上服役了
I've served on Battlestar since I was 18 years old.
珀伽索斯 哥伦比亚 亚特兰大  卡拉狄加
The Pegasus, Columbia, Atlantia, Galactica...
别像军人一样和我说话!
Don't talk to me like you're a soldier!
你不是军人!
You are not a soldier!
老头子一向对你心慈手软
The old man always had a soft spot for you.
让他决定怎么处置你吧
Let him decide what to do with you.
上校  你要相信我
Colonel, you gotta believe me.
我不是赛昂人
I am not a Cylon.
我从没做过任何危害阿达玛的事
I'd never do anything to hurt Adama.
我爱老头子
I love the old man.
你的女友也那么说过
That's what your girlfriend said.
把他给我带出去!
Get him the hell out of here!
上士
Chief.
我以为你还在科波上
I thought you were on Kobol.
别..和我...说话
Don't you talk to me.
别靠近我  别碰我
Don't come near me. Don't touch me. If you do,
不然我发誓  我会杀了你
I swear, I will kill you.
封锁线周围没有赛昂武士的动静
No sign of Centurions on the perimeter.
我可不喜欢这样
I don't like it.
人形赛鬼子从来都不会单独行动
Human toasters don't go anywhere alone.
以为他们是诱饵? 不
Think they're bait? No.
两个赛昂人不可能大白天就开车来到这里
A pair of Cylons don't just drive up here in broad daylight,
尤其是上周我们攻击了那护送队后
not after we hit that convoy last week.
他妈的
Frakking A.
得了  不管了
All right, screw it.
传话给周围的弟兄
Pass the word for everybody to sight in.
要让这俩赛昂人到死
I want to blow these Cylons away
都不知道怎么死的
before they ever knew what hit them.
好的
Good.
我们得查明我们所处的方位
We got to figure out where the hell we are.
为什么?你不知道?
Why? You don't know?
你是导航员
You're the navigator.
可你是司机
You were driving.
好  我们可以去"嘉布丝点"
STARBUCK: All right, we can head toward Cobb's Point.
那里有一个备用小型机场
There's an emergency airstrip there.
不  我去过那边
No, I've been...
咱们还是向西南方向走吧
I was thinking we could head southwest towards...
听到了吗?
Do you hear that?
闯入了禁地?
Drive through a lot of bad neighborhoods?
小心驶得万年船
Better safe than sorry.
知道了
I hear that.
我们在这儿是坐以待毙
We're sitting ducks down here!
你去  我掩护  为什么要我去?!
You go, I'll cover. Why me?
少废话  好啦!
Don't start. Fine!
准备好了吗?  恩
Ready? Yeah!
去吧!
Go!
5个人  分布在1点到9点的位置  50米处
Five of them, spread out between nine and one! 50 meters.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
走!
Go!
没看到那边有赛昂武士
I didn't see any shiny silver out there.
我看对方是人类
I think we're dealing with the human variety.
但愿如此  他们可没机器那么凶猛
Hope so. They're not as tough as mechanicals.
恩
Yeah.
可他们还是会流血  真烦
They do bleed good, though. You gotta like that.
离开这里!走!
HELO: Let's get out of here. Come on.
他们把上士和布玛儿关到了一起
They locked the Chief up with Boomer.
泰认为他是赛昂人
Tigh thinks he's a Cylon.
我知道  我现在要去见上校
I know. I'm going to see the Colonel now.
我看他想让我想个办法洗脱上士的嫌疑或是...
I think he wants me to find a way to clear the Chief or...
或是什么?  把他像垃圾一样丢进过渡舱吗?
Or what? Throw him out the airlock like a piece of garbage?
如果阿达玛指挥官在的话  才不会这样
If Commander Adama were in charge this would never happen.
是  可他不在  对吧?
Yes, but he's not in charge, is he?
可我认识上士几年了  他可不是赛鬼子
But I've known the Chief for years. He's no toaster.
他曾与已被认作是赛鬼子的…
He was involved with Lieutenant Valerii,
沃莱瑞中尉交往
who most certainly is a toaster.
那么说可是种族歧视  我不喜欢
NO. 6: That word is racist. I don't like it.
当然
Sure,
与她交往是他一时的糊涂
he's shown some bad judgment getting involved with her.
可那并不代表他就是赛鬼子
But that doesn't mean he's a toaster.
你得救救他
You've got to help him.
说话啊  盖尤斯
Say something, Gaius.
告诉我你不会用这些带有种族歧视意味的称号
Tell me you won't have racial epithets used in your presence.
非常抱歉
I'm very sorry.
我本打算告诉上校  我无能为力
I was going to tell the Colonel there's nothing I can do.
显然  我所研制的赛昂人探测器并不好用
The Cylon detector I developed doesn't work. Clearly.
不
No.
你得救救他
You've got to help him.
你的孩子将是半个赛鬼子
Your child's gonna be half toaster.
你作何感想呢?
How does that make you feel?
我高兴的不得了
Nothing could make me happier.
我只是不知道自己可能会说些什么  失陪
I just don't know what I'd possibly say. Excuse me.
他救过你!
CALLY: He helped you.
他没对任何人说你在科波上的所做作为
He didn't tell anyone what you did on Kobol.
你对克莱斯当干了什么
What you did to Crashdown.
我对克莱斯当所做的救了你一命
What I did to Crashdown saved your life.
你是在恐吓我?
Are you blackmailing me?
救上士就是挽救你自己  博士
Help the Chief, help yourself, Doctor.
是的  博士
NO. 6: Yes, Doctor.
那才是你的强项  不是吗?
That's what you're best at, isn't it?
战舰日志
Deck log.
你的赛昂人探测器到底是怎么回事  博士?
What the hell's the matter with your Cylon detector, Doctor?
你给了刺客可乘之机
You gave the assassin a pass.
对  可那是贝塔版本的  初步测试
Yes, but that was a beta test. A preliminary.
显然  方法还没得以完善  而她乘虚而入
Clearly, I haven't perfected my methodology and she slipped through.
燃料报告
DUALLA: Fuel report.
那你到底是什么意思?
TIGH: What the hell are you telling me here,
我们要从头开始?
that we are back to square one?
大家的结果都不是肯定的?
That no one's results are definitive? No, I...
我们根本不知道我们中谁是赛昂人?
That we have no way of knowing who are the Cylons among us?
不  我是说从沃莱瑞的测…
BALTAR: I'm not saying that. I'm saying since Valerii's test...
刺客的测试  我已研究出一套新方法
Since the assassin's test, I've developed a new set of protocols,
可以完全避免原来的突然发生的错误
which should eliminate any errors,
以及异常 还更快捷
anomalies, that cropped up earlier.
如果你让我检测一下上士的血样
If you let me test the Chief's blood,
我也许会查明
I might be able to tell once and for all...
没有也许  我要肯定的答案
No if. I want a definitive answer,
别用你那一套专业术语和我喋喋不休
no more of your weasly techno-babble.
他是不是赛昂人
He's a Cylon or he's not,
你快去把事情给我办好
so get down there and do something right for a change.
我是副总统
I am the Vice President.
法律上讲  如果总统无法执政
Legally speaking, if the president is incapacitated,
我就该代替她
shouldn't I take over her duties?
法律上讲  我宣布实施了戒严令
Legally speaking, I have declared martial law
这就使你无足轻重
and that makes you nobody.
所以  除非你想和罗丝琳一起关禁闭
So, unless you want to join Roslin in the brig,
不然我建议你还是快去工作
I suggest you get to work.
很高兴见到你  上校
It's good to see you, Colonel.
受尽凌辱的你不厌烦吗?
Aren't you getting tired of the continual humiliation?
机器和人类都没把你放在眼里
The disrespect from mechanics and colonels alike?
你的意思是?
What do you think?
也许是时候该做出点对策了
Maybe it's time to do something about it?
长官  这是什么?
GAETA: Sir? What's this?
舰队里的船长报告平民中有人抗议
The fleet captains are reporting protests among civilians,
示威  请愿  甚至是消极抵抗
demonstrations, petitions, even some civil disobedience,
全部是针对戒严令
all over the declaration of martial law.
长官  这还有
Sir, there's more.
艾拓恩提炼船停止提炼锑砾钼
The Tauranian refining vessel has stopped refining tylium.
他们说如果无政府统治…
They say if they don't have a voice in the government...
什么?
What?
他们的船长说一旦恢复平民政府
Their captain says they'll send fuel
就立即派送燃料
once a civilian government has been restored,
另有三艘船表示除非总统恢复职权
and, three other ships are also refusing to re-supply Galactica
否则拒绝为卡拉狄加再补给
until the President's reinstated.
我从作战信息中心那里
And I got a note from Combat,
接到了有关锑砾钼再补给问题的通知
warning about problems with tylium re-supply,
所以在作进一步通知以前请注意燃料的使用量
so watch your fuel burn until further notice.
有什么问题吗?
Questions?
你什么时候回来打牌?
When you coming back to the card game?
恐怕下班后
I'm afraid when I'm off duty,
我就要去享受牢狱的快乐生活  直到...
I'll be enjoying the intimate surroundings of the brig until...
直到再作通知
well, until further notice.
回来吧  我们想你了  上尉
Come on back. We miss you, Captain.
我们可以拿到你那里玩
We could bring the game to you.
可我怀疑泰上校是否会同意
Somehow I doubt Col. Tigh would approve.
拜托  明天就有一局
There's one going on tomorrow night!
好了  好了
Hey, all right. All right.
算了吧
Hey, knock it off!
早上好  长官
Morning, sir.
中士  我们走吧
Sergeant. Shall we?
早上好  长官
Morning, sir.
早上好  小杜  很高兴在这见到你
Morning, Dee. Fancy meeting you here.
我只是顺路
I was just on my way, sir.
嗨 各位 还好吗?  小杜?
Hey, guys. How's it going, Dee?
挺好的  多谢
Good, thanks.
我父亲今天怎么样?
How's my father today?
阿达玛指挥官还是老样子  上尉
Commander Adama's the same, Captain.
注射了镇静剂
He's sedated.
手术后一直很舒适地休息着
Resting comfortably since the surgery.
舰队里倒是正酝酿着麻烦事
Trouble brewing in the fleet, though.
真让我吃惊
Oh, I'm shocked.
什么样的麻烦?
What kind of trouble?
戒严令的效果并不太好
Martial law isn't going down too well.
抗议  示威
Protests, demonstrations,
有些船甚至拒绝为卡拉狄加再补给
some ships are even refusing to re-supply Galactica.
现在是蜜月时期
And this is the honeymoon period.
独裁者会做什么呢?
What's a dictator to do?
我希望...
Yeah, I wish...
我希望是你来当指挥官  长官
I wish you were in command, sir.
小杜
Dee...
他老是喝酒  喝了好多
He's hitting the bottle. A lot.
多谢陪我  杜亚拉中士
Thank you for the company, Petty Officer Dualla.
不客气  长官
You're welcome, sir.
你没事吧  宝贝儿?
You okay, baby?
不  有事  脑袋像是…
No, I'm not okay. My head feels like
要从脖子上掉下来了一样
it's gonna roll off my shoulders.
在研究什么?
What're you working on?
我正在想办法解决再补给问题
I'm trying to figure out how to solve our re-supply problem
一半舰队都已经罢工了
now that half the fleet has gone out on strike.
真的?
Are you serious?
恩  是真的
Yes, I'm serious.
我应该与各船长
I should probably call a summit.
举行高峰会谈
Sit down with all the ship captains
解释当前情况
and explain the situation and tell them
告诉他们我为什么要实施戒严令
why I had to declare martial law.
去他们的  你还用得着和他们解释吗
Screw them. Like you have to explain yourself to them.
没什么大不了的  也许还能缓和一下局势
It wouldn't hurt. Might cool things down a little.
怎么?
What?
没什么
Nothing.
不  只是...
I don't know, it's...
你是老大
You're the boss.
不该由我来告诉你该怎么做
Far be it for me to tell you how to do your job.
我知道你不喜欢
I know that's one of your issues.
你就说吧
Just say it.
不知道  只觉得有些过于感情化了
I don't know, it just feels kind of touchy-feely.
比如 "大家都请坐
You know, "Let's all sit down
谈一下对戒严令的看法"
"and talk about how we feel about martial law. "
比尔可不会那么做
Bill would never do that.
但想怎么做随便你
But you gotta do what you gotta do,
我的意思是比尔可能永远都站不起来了
I mean, Bill may never get on his feet again.
甜心
Honey.
甜心  你按你自己的想法去处理这事
Honey, you handle this the way you want.
他们最终会遵从你的决定
They'll respect that eventually.
我是副长
This is the XO.
盖塔先生 把以下电文传给各船长
Mr. Gaeta, send the following to all ships captains.
电文如下
Message begins,
为此船再补给的行动没有..重复..没有选择的余地
"Re-supply operations of this ship are not, repeat, not optional.
各船立即重新开始安排补给
"All ships to recommence scheduled supply runs immediately.
不服从命令将作严肃处理
"Failure to comply will result in stern measures. "
电文结束
Message ends.
你现在开心了?
You happy now?
我就位
STARBUCK: I'll flank!
我去交火
I'll draw fire!
想都别想
No, no.
喂
Hi.
我们不是赛昂人
We're not Cylons.
对  你是人类
Right. You're human.
你有灵魂  你在小溪中游泳
You have a soul. You swim in the stream.
这我们都听过
We heard it all before.
殖民舰队  注意到这身制服了吗?
Hey, Colonial Fleet. Notice the uniforms?
可不  我们也见过穿制服的赛昂人
Yeah, right. We've seen Cylons in uniform before.
我们是人类  恩  可不是吗
We're human. Yeah, right.
卡布里卡上的人都死光了
STARBUCK: Everyone on Caprica is dead.
你就没死
You're not.
我刚到这儿  报一下名吧
I just got here. I want to hear some names.
我是安德斯
I'm Anders.
萨缪尔·安德斯
Samuel T. Anders?
恩  对
Yeah, that's right.
乔曼  雷丽  石电
SAM: That's Jo-Man, Rally, Ten Point...
苏尚  科利基  莫里斯·芬克
Sue-shaun, Crip-key, Morris Fink.
卡拉  这些人是"卡布里卡掠夺者队"的
Kara, these are the Caprica Buccaneers.
我看不是
I don't think so.
拿球来试试  小娘们儿  有你好瞧的
Give me a ball, little girl. I'll shove it up your ass.
拜托  试试看
Please. Try.
好  大家都不错
Okay, since we're all getting along so well,
咱就别拿枪互相指着了
can people stop pointing their guns at us?
一支职业金字塔球赛队怎么在核浩劫中活了下来?
How does a professional pyramid team survive a nuclear holocaust?
赛昂人袭击的时候我们正在山里
We were in the mountains when the Cylons attacked.
在做高原训练
High altitude training.
从那以后就一直在逃亡
We've been on the run ever since.
干什么?
Doing what?
袭击军械库夺取弹药  寻找抗辐射药物
Raiding military stores for ammo, anti-radiation meds,
见到赛鬼子就杀
and plugging toasters whenever they show up.
和我们一样
Same as us.
好
Okay.
你们与爱诺朗的季后赛
How many foul breaks did you have
犯规次数是多少?
in the play-off against Aerilon?
你是开玩笑吧?
You're kidding, right?
说不对就吃枪子儿
You either have the answer or you have a bullet.
3次
Three.
错  4次
Wrong. Four.
3次
Three.
最后一次通过重播判为无效
Last one was called back on instant replay.
他说的对  星芭儿
HELO: He's right, Starbuck.
我那场比赛损失了20库比特
I lost 20 cubits on that game.
好吧  暂时没事了
Fine, for now.
数到三
On three.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
你们真是逊毙了  知道吗?
You know you guys suck, right?
投球不中  传球失误
You can't shoot, you can't pass,
肯定也就无法得分啦
and you sure as hell can't take a point.
人人都要说三到四啊
Everyone's a critic.
这是您的药  总统女士
Here's your medication, Madam President.
还有一些从厨房带来的东西
And a little something from the galley.
谢谢你  温纳下士
Thank you, Cpl. Venner.
卡马拉和甘草
Chamalla and licorice.
要些不?
Would you like some?
我讨厌甘草
I hate licorice.
我也是
Me, too.
有趣的是他仍然称呼您为总统女士
It's interesting he still calls you, "Madam President".
您在外面还有很多支持者
You still have a lot of supporters out there.
我能感觉到即将发生一些丑陋的事
Something ugly is coming. I can feel it.
长官  提炼船的船长仍拒绝合作
Sir, the refinery captain's still not cooperating.
又有7艘集装箱船拒绝再补给
And now seven other container ships
食物  药物  甚至是咖啡
are refusing to release their supplies, food, medicine, even coffee.
咖啡?越来越荒唐了
Coffee? This is getting ridiculous.
去他妈的!该给他们点颜色看看了
Frak this. It's time to get their attention.
我要派陆战队
I'm sending in the Marines.
派一架猛禽号和一队陆战突袭队
I want a Raptor and an armed Marine boarding party
前往任何一艘拒绝再补给命令的船只
for every ship refusing the re-supply order.
长官  我们人力极其短缺
Sir, we're stretched pretty thin on manpower.
我看没有足够陆战队
I'm not sure we have enough Marine non-coms
指挥那么多突袭队  长官
to command that many boarding parties.
如有必要  调动驾驶员和船上官员
Pull pilots and deck officers
去指挥突袭队
to command the boarding parties if you have to.
告诉他们去那里拿回补给
Tell them to get over there and bring back the supplies.
不论用什么方法
Whatever it takes.
快去办吧  中尉
Make it happen, Lieutenant.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
大家  退后  知道吗?
People, step back. All right.
我们只是来拿补给品的
We're just here for the supplies!
别挡道  不要有人因此受伤
Stay out of our way and no one gets hurt!
最后再说一次  退后  知道吗?
PALLADINO: For the last time! Step back, all right!
退后!
Get back!
停火
Cease fire!
4名平民死亡
TIGH: Four civilian dead.
这他妈的是怎么搞的?
How the frak could this have happened?
你以为呢  天才?
What did you expect, genius?
你派驾驶员来维持人群秩序
You put a pilot in charge of crowd control.
帕伦蒂诺!
Palladino!
是你下命令向人群开枪的吗?
Did you give the order to shoot on that crowd?
不是  长官  当然不是
No, sir. Of course not.
人群把我们团团围住了
The crowd surrounded us.
他们有武器吗?
Were they armed?
没有  长官
No, sir, but
可你不知道当时的情景  他们叫骂我们
you had to be there. They were yelling and screaming at us
然后他们变得异常暴力  向我们扔东西  罐子…
and then it got violent. They started throwing things, canisters,
咖啡
coffee, I think.
咖啡?
Coffee?
你们向他们射击就因为他们扔咖啡?
You shot people for throwing coffee?
当时人群失去了控制  他们在逼迫我们
The crowd was out of control, they were pressing in on us.
我的人受了伤  有人开了一枪
My men were getting hurt. Somebody took a shot,
我不知道是谁
I don't know who it was.
然后就一片混乱
Then all hell broke loose.
最需要你的时候  比尔  就是现在了
If ever we needed you, Bill, it's right now.
军队向手无寸铁的平民开枪
Troops shooting unarmed civilians.
这太卑劣了
This is a travesty.
他真的做得太过分了
He has truly stepped over the line.
这在舰队中将引起轩然大波
It'll cause an explosion in the fleet.
媒体将以此大作文章
The press will have a field day.
舰队将走向分裂
The ships will begin to splinter.
赛昂人就会慢慢蚕食我们
The Cylons will be able to eliminate us a few ships at a time.
我们得马上从这里出去
I've got to get out of here now.
下士
Corporal.
我和你在一起
I'm right with you.
很高兴你这么说
I'm so glad you said that.
我要带比利和伊罗霞一起走
I wanna take Billy and Elosha with me.
这是当然
Of course you do.
我已经有个办法能让我们到达机库
I've worked out a way of getting us in the hangar deck
还能弄架猛禽号
and I can get us a Raptor.
但我们仍要获得离舰许可
But we're still gonna need clearance to get off the ship.
我知道怎么能得到
I know how to get that.
是吗?
You do?
问题是离舰后去哪儿?
The question is, where do we go once we get off this ship?
我们要在舰队中找个能藏身
We'll have to find some place to hide in the fleet
并且能得到人民支持的地方
while we rally support among the people.
我心里有数了
APOLLO: I've got an idea about that.
可你不会喜欢的
You're not gonna like it.
我根本就无法胜任  本来就不行
I'm not cut out for this. I never was.
别那么说  索尔
Don't talk like that, Saul.
这是你的机遇
This is your moment.
我和比尔  分工协作  这是约定
Me and Bill, side by side, that was the deal.
本就不该是我一个人孤军奋战
It was never supposed to be me alone.
无论喜欢与否  都是你在指挥
Well, like it or not, you're in command.
所以就要你去应付
So you better deal with it.
我不想去应付这些
I don't want to "deal with it".
不想指挥  你还不明白吗?
I do not want a command, don't you get it?
老天  我为什么要听你的?
Jeez, why do I listen to you?
你在说什
What are you talking...
我可没叫你派兵去那艘船
I never told you to send troops out to that ship.
对  你没让我派过兵
No, no. You didn't tell me to send troops anywhere.
你只是操纵这一切 你一直都是这样
You just manipulate. You always do.
话里有话
You put the knife in and you twist it.
好啊  你自己办事不力还怪罪到我的头上来了?
Oh, right. You're gonna blame me for your own inadequacies?
我没怪你  艾伦
I'm not blaming you, Ellen.
你他妈的也太逆来顺受了
You are so frakking passive
要不是我助你一臂之力...   别提了
that if I didn't push you... Well, forget it.
你永远都是醉鬼一个
...you'd never get your head out of that frakking bottle
一事无成
and do anything!
我警告你  我告诉你
I'm warning you, I'm telling...
滚开
Get your...
我好爱你
Oh, yeah. I love you so much.
闭嘴  艾伦
Shut up, Ellen.
我猜你一定很狠我
I guess you really must hate me.
我不知道这么说还有没有用
I don't know if it makes any difference right now
但真的很抱歉把你卷了进来
but I'm really sorry you got pulled into this.
你知道我们之间
You know, what we had...
没有任何关系
Was nothing. Nothing.
你是机器  而我不是
You're a machine. I'm not.
不管我是什么  我知道自己的感受
Well, whatever I am, I know how I felt.
软件没有感情
Software doesn't have feelings.
开门
BALTAR: Open cell.
我从没想过去伤害你
I never meant to hurt you.
请让我们单独呆会儿
I'd like some privacy, please.
我不会有事的  谢谢
I'll be fine, thank you.
两位晚上过的怎么样?
And how are we this evening?
你想怎样?
What do you want?
我是来决定你是否是赛昂人的
I'm here to determine whether you're a Cylon or not.
请把袖子挽好
Your arm, please.
他的测试可不怎么灵光
His test doesn't work too well.
他说我通过了
I mean, he gave me the green light.
测试是...
The test works
有效的
just fine.
上士
Chief?
我骗了你  莎伦
BALTAR: I lied to you, Sharon.
我为了个人目的 而对整个舰队
I covered up your true nature from the rest of the fleet
隐瞒了你的真面目
for my own purposes.
你把他怎么了?他没呼吸了
What did you do to him? He's not breathing!
不  他现在可快死了  莎伦
No, he's dying right now, Sharon.
我可以救他
I can save him,
除非你告诉我舰队里还有多少个赛昂人
if you tell me how many Cylons there are left in the fleet.
我不知道  可他没脉搏了
I don't know, but I'm not getting a pulse!
不  你知道
Yes, you do.
在你那所谓的
Now, buried, deep down in that thing
潜意识深处  你知道有
you call a subconscious, you know.
有多少?  我不知道!
How many? I don't know!
他的时间可不多了  莎伦
He doesn't have time for this, Sharon.
他的器官要衰竭了
His organs are shutting down.
10秒钟内  他就会脑死亡
In 10 seconds time, he'll experience complete brain stem death.
到底多少个?
Now, how many?
你爱他吗  莎伦?
Do you love him, Sharon?
只有你能救他
Only you can save him.
十  九…
Ten, nine...
你爱他吗?  你爱他吗  莎伦?
Do you love him? Do you love him, Sharon?
8个  有8个
Eight! There are eight!
好了  把武器卸下来  快!
All right, let's get these weapons unloaded! Let's go!
今天早些时候袭击了一个军械库 在这里以北18克利克的地方
We raided an armory earlier today, about 18 klicks north.
收获了不少玩具
Brought home a lot of toys.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
特尔斐联盟高中
Delphi Union High School.
赛鬼子不会巡逻到这里
Toasters don't patrol this area.
食宿的好地方
It's a good place to get some shut-eye, a bite to eat.
这里有多少人?
How many people you have here?
53人
53.
原来差不多有100人 可上周中了赛鬼子的埋伏
We had almost 100 before the toasters ambushed us last week.
快!  还有金字塔球赛队吗?
Let's go! More pyramid teams?
没有  只有我们卡布里卡队
No. Just us C-Bucs.
其他的都是侥幸活下来的人 和一些旅行者
The rest are survivalists, hikers, mostly.
存有多少抗辐射剂?
How's your stock of anti-radiation meds?
在朝圣湾奇袭了几家医院
SAM: We raided a couple of hospitals down in Pilgrim Bay.
我算了一下够我们用3个月的了
I figure we've got enough for about three months.
走去给你们找个住的地方  来吧
Let's get you some bunk space. Come on.
53人?  算不上是一支军队
Fifty-three, huh? Not exactly an army.
可要比我们两人只身
A hell of a lot better than the two of us
攻打一座空军基地
if we're going to assault an airbase,
还要偷个重装突袭机逃离这该死的星球强多了
steal a Heavy Raider and get the frak off this planet.
我就呆一会儿
I'll just be a moment.
医生
Doctor,
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
但这将是违法  危险 且与你作为军人的誓言背道而驰的
But it's illegal, dangerous, and in violation of your oath as an officer.
你是一个差劲的推销员
You're a lousy salesman.
下士  温纳
Corporal. Cpl. Venner.
我只想告诉你总统是多么感激
I just want to tell you how much the President appreciates
你为她所做的一些小事
all the little things you do for her.
只要能让她好受些就行
Hey, anything I can do to make things easier for her.
好极了
Great.
她有个特殊的请求
She has a special request.
请签名  长官
If I could just get your signature, sir.
为什么要关闭B堤道?
Why are we closing down Causeway B?
整合测试  长官
Integrity testing, sir.
赛鬼子侵入的时候  毁坏挺严重的
It got chewed up pretty bad when the toasters boarded us
那里的压力有些下降
and we've been getting some pressure drops in there.
告诉他们把它修好
Tell them to get it fixed.
不好意思
Sorry.
中尉
Lieutenant.
这几天一切都一团糟
Things are pretty frakked up these days.
恩  大多数时候是这样的
Things are pretty frakked up most days.
如果有人不开心
If people are upset
应该通过正常渠道解决问题
they should go through proper channels, so...
我不太清楚你
I'm not sure I understand what you...
我刚才在做维修核对工作
I was running some maintenance checks
查到在过去几小时内
and detected a series of scrambled calls
有人打了几个加密电话
going out over the past few hours.
你不知道这是谁干的  是吧?
You wouldn't happen to know anything about that, would you?
不知道  长官  未记录电话违反规定
No, sir. Off-log calls are against regs.
说的对
That's right.
我知道你不会同意的
I'm sure you won't approve.
可这我早料到了
But I guess that's nothing new.
我只想让你知道这...
I just want you to know that this...
这不是你我之间的事情
This isn't about you and me.
再见  爸爸
Goodbye, Dad.
你是来帮忙的  还是怎么的?
You gonna help out here or what?
他们把上士关了起来  你知道吗
They're putting the Chief in there, you know.
我才不在乎关的是大鹦鹉还是什么
I don't care if they put a giant parakeet in here.
上校让我们造牢房  我们就造
The Colonel says we build a cell, we build a cell.
这么说不对  他是我们的人
This isn't right. He's one of us.
不  他是赛昂人中的一员
No. He's one of them.
一直都是这样子  只是我们没觉察到
He always was. We just never saw it.
不  他是无辜的  她骗了他
No, he's innocent. She tricked him.
好忠诚啊  你也上了他?
Such loyalty. Were you frakking him, too?
你要埋怨别人  最好去埋怨布玛儿
You want to get pissed at someone, you get pissed at Boomer.
是她连累上士坐牢的  可不是我们
She's the one who put the Chief in this cell here, not us.
专家?
Specialist?
晚上好  长官
Evening, sir.
晚上好  小杜  很高兴在这见到你
Evening, Dee. Fancy meeting you here.
一切安排妥当了?
Everything set?
是的
Roger that.
抱歉  上尉  今天不能闲聊了
Sorry, Captain. Can't chit-chat today.
上尉
Captain.
我的猛禽号上的弹药输送出了问题
I'm having trouble with the ordinance tracking on my Raptor, sir.
无法更换
I can't get it to cycle.
改变计划  各位  不能去休息了
Oh, change of plans, boys. Instead of getting some rack time
我要去帮一下中尉
I'm gonna take a minute to do the Lieutenant's job for her.
是  长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
你带路
After you.
谢了
Thank you.
好  狠点打  但别太狠
Okay, make it look good, but not too good.
站住!
Hold it!
你可能知道我是谁
Private, do you know who I am?
好
Good.
你我有些共同点
You and I have something in common.
我们都谨记要保卫
We each took an oath to protect and defend the Articles of Colonization.
像我们大家的民主生活一样
Those Articles are under attack,
那些条款正在被践踏
as is our entire democratic way of life.
现在  我的职责促使我不能对此坐视不管
Now, my duty won't let me stand here and allow that to happen.
所以我要通过那扇舱门  离开这船
So I intend to go through that hatch and get off this ship.
该死  他们现在该到了
Damn it. They should be here by now.
站到一边或杀了我
You can either stand aside or you can shoot me.
你来决定你的职责是什么
You'll have to decide where your duty lies.
总统女士...
Madam President...
总统女士  这边请
Madam President, this way.
比利
Oh, Billy...
总统女士...
Madam President,
我不能和您一起上船
I'm not getting on that ship with you.
怎么?
What?
我明白您要做什么
I understand what you're trying to do.
但这将导致舰队产生派别
But it's gonna divide the fleet.
至少将会引起叛乱来反抗阿达玛
At the very best, it'll create an insurgency against Adama
更糟糕的话  就是内战
and at the worst, a civil war.
我不会去冒这个险
Taking part in that is a line that I won't cross.
时间不多了
APOLLO: We do not have a lot of time.
祝你平安
I wish you well.
医用机2-7  检验器为绿色
Dustoff two-seven, Checkers green,
准备起飞执行医疗任务
ready for launch on medical mission.
请求准予起飞
Request clearance.
见到你真好  没事吧?
Good to see you. You okay?
没事  我几乎是被抬来的
I think so. My feet barely touched the ground getting here.
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean.
医用机2-7  准许从3号全流道舱门起飞
MAN ON RADIO: Dustoff two-seven, Standard port three departure approved.
可以起飞
Cleared for launch.
3号全流道舱门起飞  照办!
Standard port three, wilco.
长官  温纳下士报告前任总统失踪
Sir, Cpl. Venner reports the former President's missing.
失踪?
Missing?
两人受伤  牢里没人
Two men down. Cell's empty.
该死的!
Damn it.
警示保安  全船二级戒备
Alert security. Set Condition Two.
禁止登舰或离舰
No one on or off the ship.
注意
Attention.
全船二级戒备
Set Condition Two throughout the ship.
重复  全船二级戒备
Repeat. Set Condition Two throughout the ship.
长官  飞行日志记录两分钟前一架载有卡托医生
Sir, flight log records a Raptor departed ship two minutes ago
执行紧急医疗任务的猛禽号离舰
with Doc Cottle on a medical emergency.
医疗?  确认一下
Medical? Confirm that.
雷达探测到他们的应答器在 方位2-8-7  弹回0-0-3
Dradis has their transponder bearing 2-8-7 carom 0-0-3.
范围2-7
Range 2-7.
通知巡逻机前去拦截
Get the CAP on the horn and have them intercept.
把阿达玛上尉从禁闭室放出来
And get Captain Adama out of the brig.
长官  卡托医生仍在舰上
Sir, Doctor Cottle is still onboard.
他说是阿波罗上尉用枪逼他…
He says he was forced to request the Raptor
索取猛禽号的
at gunpoint by Apollo.
他奶奶的
Son-of-a-bitch.
小杜  给我接通那架猛禽号
Dee, put me through to that Raptor.
巡逻机已发现目标
GAETA: CAP has visual on the target.
调头回来  阿波罗
Turn that ship around, Apollo,
不然我命令巡逻机击落你们
or I'll order the CAP to shoot you down.
我们不会回去了
APOLLO: We're not turning back.
我会下命令的!
I'll do it.
别以为你是老头子的儿子 我就不敢这么做
And don't think I won't just because you're the old man's son.
要来就来吧  卡拉狄加
Then do what you have to do, Galactica.
阿波罗通话完毕
Apollo out.
向机首前方开火
Fire across their bow.
热狗  我是卡拉狄加
Hotdog, Galactica.
向机首前方开火  确认
Fire across their bow. Acknowledge.
照办  卡拉狄加
Wilco, Galactica.
热狗报告他们并未调头
Hotdog reports they're not turning around, sir.
他们现在在哪里?
Where are they now?
雷达显示接近星云九号
Dradis shows them approaching Cloud 9.
长官  如果他们入港  我们就弄丢他们了
GAETA: Sir, if they dock, we may lose them.
星云九号是舰队中最为繁忙的运输中心之一
Cloud 9 is one of the busiest transport hubs in the fleet.
飞梭来往频繁
Shuttles are coming and going constantly.
在我们在关闭空管之前
If they board one and take off,
他们就可以乘机离去
it'll be before we can shut down air traffic.
卡拉狄加  我是热狗  请求指示
Galactica, Hotdog. Request instructions.
卡拉狄加  我是热狗 我需要进一步指示
Galactica, Hotdog. I need further instructions.
是否开火
Do I fire or not?
小杜  告诉热狗不要开火
Dee, tell Hotdog to hold his fire.
重复  不要开火
Repeat, weapons hold. Do not fire.
热狗  我是卡拉狄加 不要开火
Hotdog, Galactica. Weapons hold.
重复  不要开火
Repeat, do not fire.
不可能是他自己干的
They couldn't have done it on their own.
是否有未记录的电话
Anybody notice off-log calls?
加密通讯?
Scrambled communications?
没有  长官  什么都没有
No, sir. Nothing.
暂时安全了
Well, we're home free for now.
见到你真好  总统女士
ZAREK: Good to see you, Madam President.
阿波罗上尉...
Captain Apollo,
泽瑞克先生在这里干什么?
what is Mr. Zarek doing here?
一旦泰冷静下来后
Once Tigh gets over his initial shock,
就会派兵来抓我们
he'll send troops out to search for us.
如果我们要想成功 我们就得不断换地方
If we're going to make it we have to keep on the move.
我考虑到泽瑞克先生
I figured Mr. Zarek here is the only one in the fleet
是这里唯一可以为我们提供庇护的人
with enough shady friends around who can possibly hide us.
我喜欢他这样的说法
I love the way he puts that.
泽瑞克先生  看来我敌人的敌人就是我的朋友了
Well, Mr. Zarek. It would seem the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
叫我汤姆吧
Call me Tom.
飞梭在等我们  我们得快点了
A shuttle's waiting, ma'am. We have to hurry.
你就这水平?
Wow, is that the best you can do?
很高兴知道把安装金字塔球场
Nice to know installing a regulation pyramid court
作为反抗军的头等大事
was one of the priorities of the Resistance.
有些东西是少不了的
Well, there are some things one cannot live without.
来吧
Let's go.
开玩笑吧?我会打你个落花流水的
SAM: Are you kidding me? I'd wipe the court with you.
那就试试吧
We'll see about that.
我曾被球探发现要去打职业比赛
I was up for the pros.
膝伤使我退出了角逐
Bum knee took me out of contention.
是这样啊
I see.
这就是如果我痛扁你的借口吗?
Is that gonna be your excuse when I kick your ass?
我的膝盖疼
"My poor knee hurts. "
至少我还有个借口
At least I have an excuse.
想不出你的借口会是什么
I can't imagine what yours is gonna be.
投的好
Nice shot.
谢了
Thanks.
多谢  博士  真的很谢谢你
Thanks, Doc. I appreciate it.
别谢我  谢她
Don't thank me. Thank her.
为什么  关她什么事?
TYROL: Why? What did she have to do with it?
一切都与她有关
BALTAR: Everything.
没什么事
Nothing.
爱情是一种奇怪且美好的东西  上士
Love is a strange and wonderful thing, Chief.
如果你曾经历过  就会心情愉快
You'd be happy you experienced it at all.
即使是和机器在一起
Even if it was with a machine.
他们会怎么处置她?
TYROL: What're they going to do to her?
他们在造一间新牢房
They're setting up a new holding facility.
会对她做测试  精神上 肉体上的测试
There will be tests, mental, physical.
把她当作实验室的小白鼠吗?
Like she's... Like she's some kind of lab rat?
是这样的
That's the idea.
这可好
This is just great.
比尔·阿达玛的宝贝儿子把你骗了
Bill Adama's little baby boy pulls the wool over your eyes
你就让他这么潇洒的走了
and you let him get away scot free.
你真成了笑柄了
You're a laughingstock.
我看你就没想当指挥官
You didn't want this command.
可别担心  你掌权的时间也不多了
Well, don't worry about it. You won't have it for much longer.
全因为你关键时刻优柔寡断
All because when push came to shove, you got shoved.
那是他的儿子
It was his son.
索尔
ADAMA: Saul.
我的船上出了什么事?
What's happening on my ship?
在通道里等着
Wait in the corridor.
艾伦  我和副长单独聊会行吗?
Ellen, can I speak to my XO?
当然可以
Of course.
慢点儿
Slow.
都出了什么事?
What's happened?
我把事情办砸了
I've frakked things up and good.
怎么会这样?
How?
我做了一些错误的决定
I made some bad calls.
这我也有过
I've done that.
不同以往
Not like these.
你是要给咱俩倒一杯吗?
You gonna pour us one of those or what?
恩
Yeah.
人们质疑我的决定…
I never had much use for people
无所谓
who second-guessed my decisions,
特别是因为他们没当过统帅
especially if they've never held a command.
也就体会不到压力有多大
They don't understand the pressure.
一条命令
You make a call
往往会关系到数千人的生命
that affects the lives of thousands
又没有可以寻求支援的人
and you have no one to turn to for backup.
你使这一切看起来轻松了
TIGH: You make it look easy.
现在你知道那是谎话了吧
You know that's a lie now.
还有很多事需要处理
A lot of pieces to pick up.
那我们就一起来处理
Then we'll pick them up together.
我儿子在哪里?
Where's my son?
婊子!
MAN: Bitch!
叛徒!
WOMAN: Traitor!
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
我爱你  上士
I love you, Chief.